Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're celebrating a very important and very special American holiday.
我是Catherine，今天我们庆祝一个非常重要且特别的美国节日。
That's right. Today we are celebrating and talking about Thanksgiving, a very, as you say, traditional and big holiday in the United States.
没错。今天我们谈论和庆祝感恩节，一个如你所说，在美国非常传统且盛大的节日。
That's right. So this year it's on November 25th. It's always on a Thursday.
没错。所以今年是11月25日。它总是在星期四。
Let's check out our dialogue to hear about what happens at this special dinner and why this is a holiday and then we'll be back to talk about it in just a moment.
让我们看看对话，听听这个特别晚餐上发生了什么，以及为什么这是个节日，然后我们稍后再回来讨论。
So, what are you doing for Thanksgiving?
那么，你感恩节打算做什么？
Not much really. It's more of an American tradition. So back home we don't really celebrate it.
其实没什么特别的。这更像是美国传统。所以在我们家乡，我们不怎么庆祝。
In fact, I'm not even sure of what exactly is being celebrated.
事实上，我甚至不确定到底在庆祝什么。
You know, it's a time to get together with all your family and be thankful for everything.
你知道，这是一个和家人团聚、感恩一切的时刻。
Yeah, but how did this holiday come to be?
是啊，但这个节日是怎么来的呢？
Well, the first settlers of Massachusetts arrived there because of religious persecution from England and King James.
嗯，马萨诸塞州的第一批定居者是因为英格兰和詹姆斯国王的宗教迫害而到达那里的。
Once in the New World, they befriended a native named Squanto who taught them how to harvest food from the area such as corn.
一到新世界，他们就和一位名叫Squanto的本地人交了朋友，他教他们如何从该地区收获食物，比如玉米。
And then what happened?
然后发生了什么？
Well, they had enough harvest for the next winter and in celebration they decided to have a big feast with the natives,
嗯，他们有足够的收成过冬，为了庆祝，他们决定和当地人一起举办一场盛宴，
giving thanks to the land and everyone for their food, health and new lives.
感谢土地和所有人给予的食物、健康和新生活。
Interesting. I am amazed how big and delicious Thanksgiving dinners are.
有趣。我很惊讶感恩节晚餐如此丰盛美味。
Come to my house for Thanksgiving. We're having turkey, pumpkin pie, mashed potatoes with gravy and lots of stuffing.
来我家过感恩节吧。我们有火鸡、南瓜派、肉汁土豆泥和很多馅料。
Count me in!
算我一个！
All right, we're back. So a very interesting holiday.
好了，我们回来了。所以这是一个非常有趣的节日。
We learned a little bit about why it's celebrated, how it came to be.
我们了解了一些关于它为什么被庆祝、如何起源的知识。
So let's take a look at some of those words now on Language Takeaway.
那么现在让我们在“语言小贴士”环节看看其中一些单词。
Language Takeaway
语言小贴士
The first word we have for you guys today on Language Takeaway is settler.
今天在“语言小贴士”环节，我们为你们准备的第一个单词是settler。
Now, a settler is a person. What kind of a person is a settler?
现在，settler指的是一个人。settler是什么样的人？
Basically, it's a person that goes to a place to settle down there or to settle there and that basically means to live there, to stay there permanently.
基本上，是指去一个地方定居下来的人，这基本上意味着在那里生活、永久待下去。
All right, but the idea with a settler is that he or she will start to build something, build a house, build a city, build a town.
好的，但settler的概念是，他或她会开始建造东西，建房子、建城市、建城镇。
So settlers go to places where there aren't very many people.
所以settler去的是人不太多的地方。
That's right. Kind of hard to be a settler now.
没错。现在想当settler有点难了。
But yeah, back then, obviously, there were so many places that were undiscovered or didn't have people and they would settle there.
但显然，那时候有很多未被发现或无人居住的地方，他们就在那里定居。
And the place where they went in the United States is called Massachusetts.
他们在美国去的地方叫马萨诸塞州。
Massachusetts. Now, this is a very long, very hard to pronounce word and I believe it comes from a local Indian language.
马萨诸塞州。这是一个很长、很难发音的词，我相信它来自当地印第安语言。
But Massachusetts, if you break it down, Massachusetts is a state.
但马萨诸塞州，如果你分解一下，马萨诸塞州是一个州。
And you might have heard of the biggest city in Massachusetts, which is Boston.
你可能听说过马萨诸塞州最大的城市，那就是波士顿。
So Boston, Massachusetts. But this is where the settlers first came when they came to America.
所以是波士顿，马萨诸塞州。但这就是定居者最初来到美国时到达的地方。
That's right. So I think if you go to Boston, it has kind of this atmosphere of the settlers and how this old little touch to it of how it used to be.
没错。所以我觉得如果你去波士顿，会有一种定居者的氛围，以及那种古老的小感觉，仿佛回到了过去。
Right. There is an old feel to Boston because unlike most places in America, Boston has been a city for over 400 years, almost 500 years.
对。波士顿有一种古老的感觉，因为与美国大多数地方不同，波士顿作为一个城市已经有400多年、将近500年的历史了。
So it's much different from places like California or Texas.
所以它和加州或德州这样的地方很不一样。
That's right. OK. So the settlers arrived to Massachusetts and they went there because of religious persecution from England and King James.
没错。好的。所以定居者到达马萨诸塞州，他们是因为英格兰和詹姆斯国王的宗教迫害而去的。
OK. So the key here is persecution. This is something that you do to someone else or this is something a government does to someone else.
好的。所以这里的关键是persecution。这是你对别人做的事，或者政府对别人做的事。
Basically, to persecute someone is to is to limit them or to attack them or to to prevent them from doing things that they want to do.
基本上，迫害某人就是限制他们、攻击他们，或者阻止他们做想做的事。
That's right. So basically, that is the reason why they left England, because the king was persecuting them.
没错。所以基本上，这就是他们离开英格兰的原因，因为国王在迫害他们。
They didn't let them be have their own religion. Right.
他们不让他们拥有自己的宗教。对。
They had this religion and the king did not approve of the religion and they felt like people were critical of them or attacking them or preventing them from practicing this religion.
他们有自己的宗教，国王不认可这个宗教，他们觉得人们批评他们、攻击他们，或者阻止他们实践这个宗教。
And so their religious persecution in England pushed them to this place, the New World.
所以他们在英格兰的宗教迫害把他们推到了这个地方，新世界。
So that's our next word. Right. That's right. The New World. And this is what they used to call the continent of United States or North America.
所以这是我们的下一个词。对。没错。新世界。这是他们过去用来称呼美国大陆或北美大陆的术语。
They used to call it the New World. All right. So New World, Old World.
他们过去叫它新世界。好的。所以新世界，旧世界。
So if we think of Europe as being the old world, America, like you're saying, Latin America, North America, these are part of the New World.
所以如果我们把欧洲看作旧世界，那么美国，就像你说的，拉丁美洲、北美，这些都是新世界的一部分。
So it's almost like they had never been discovered before. Right. So, yeah, basically everyone was concentrated in Europe at that time.
所以这几乎就像它们从未被发现过一样。对。所以，基本上，那时所有人都集中在欧洲。
And then when they went to the West, they went to the New World. And obviously, when they arrived, it wasn't empty.
然后当他们向西走时，他们去了新世界。显然，当他们到达时，那里并不是空的。
They had people there. And we say that they are the natives of that land.
那里有人。我们说他们是那片土地的本地人。
OK, so a native of some place is someone who comes from there originally. All right.
好的，所以某个地方的native是指最初来自那里的人。好的。
So if I came to America in 1500, there were Native American Indians who were living there.
所以如果我在1500年来到美国，那里有美洲原住民印第安人生活着。
And so they're the natives of this place. Now, can you use that nowadays? Can you say I am a native of Italy?
所以他们是这个地方的本地人。现在，你可以在今天用这个词吗？你能说“我是意大利本地人”吗？
I'm a native of Italy. I'm a native of Chicago. Yes, you can.
我是意大利本地人。我是芝加哥本地人。是的，可以。
It's a little bit, you know, it's a little bit less common than saying I'm from Chicago or I'm from Italy, but it's also correct.
这有点，你知道，比说“我来自芝加哥”或“我来自意大利”少见一些，但也是正确的。
OK, but in this case, we're talking about the natives as the people who were already there.
好的，但在这个案例中，我们谈论的native是指已经在那里的人。
Yes, Native American Indians. Like Squanto. Like Squanto. That's the name of that Native American Indian who was there.
是的，美洲原住民印第安人。比如Squanto。比如Squanto。那是那个美洲原住民印第安人的名字。
And this native named Squanto taught them how to harvest food from the area such as corn.
这个名叫Squanto的本地人教他们如何从该地区收获食物，比如玉米。
So this is the interesting part of the story. It is. Basically, these two groups worked together.
所以这是故事中有趣的部分。是的。基本上，这两个群体合作了。
You have Native American Indians and settlers, and they worked together to make a meal and to survive, basically.
你有美洲原住民印第安人和定居者，他们一起工作，制作一顿饭，基本上是为了生存。
And to harvest food, to harvest, the key here is that it's a verb. It's something you do to crops or like corn or potatoes.
还有收获食物，harvest，这里的关键是它是一个动词。这是你对庄稼做的事，比如玉米或土豆。
And you take them out from the field and you bring them home.
你把它们从田里取出来带回家。
Right. So in this case, the corn is growing out of the land. And if you go out and cut it down and take it, you are harvesting corn.
对。所以在这个案例中，玉米从地里长出来。如果你出去把它割下来拿走，你就是在收获玉米。
You are you're picking it, collecting it.
你是在采摘它、收集它。
Exactly. And so they harvested the food and they have a very big meal.
没错。所以他们收获了食物，然后吃了一顿大餐。
So we do want to talk about the special meal here that features all of this harvested food.
所以我们确实想谈谈这顿特色餐，它包含了所有这些收获的食物。
Let's take a look at some of those words in Language Takeaway Part 2.
让我们在“语言小贴士第二部分”中看看其中一些单词。
All right. So talking about the foods. Now, obviously, the tradition is that you have this big meal together.
好的。所以谈到食物。现在，显然，传统是你和家人一起吃这顿大餐。
And the one thing that is, I think, a given is that you have a big turkey.
而我认为，一件理所当然的事是你会有一只大火鸡。
That's right. So a turkey is a bird. They make very funny sounds, don't they?
没错。所以火鸡是一种鸟。它们会发出很有趣的声音，对吧？
Right. Like gobble, gobble, gobble.
对，像咯咯、咯咯、咯咯。
But they they're very big. They run around and they have this red part under their neck and beaks and everything.
但它们很大，到处跑，脖子下面有红色的部分，还有喙等等。
So it's a very commonly eaten food for Thanksgiving. But people can eat it anytime.
所以这是感恩节非常常吃的食物。但人们随时都可以吃。
Yeah. This is a weird thing. I usually don't see turkey too much, if not during Thanksgiving.
是啊。这有点奇怪。我通常除了感恩节，很少看到火鸡。
Like I don't see somebody like a restaurant offering turkey.
比如我没见过餐馆提供火鸡。
No, you don't. But you do see it in delis like a roast turkey sandwich.
不，你不会。但你在熟食店会看到，比如烤火鸡三明治。
Yes, this is true.
是的，这倒是真的。
Because turkey is very healthy.
因为火鸡很健康。
OK. So we have turkey. We also have pumpkin pie. So pumpkin pie.
好的。所以我们有火鸡。我们还有南瓜派。所以南瓜派。
Pumpkin pie. This is a classic. You've heard of apple pie.
南瓜派。这是经典。你听说过苹果派。
But pumpkin pie is a baked dessert that is filled with some pumpkin filling.
但南瓜派是一种填充了南瓜馅料的烘焙甜点。
So as you know, pumpkin or may know pumpkin is a big...
所以如你所知，南瓜可能是一种大...
It's a gourd.
它是一种葫芦。
Yeah. I think it's kind of vegetable.
是的。我觉得它有点像蔬菜。
Kind of like a vegetable. It's big and orange. And basically this is a... It's kind of sweet, right? The insides.
有点像蔬菜。它又大又橙。基本上这是一种... 它有点甜，对吧？里面的部分。
It is. It's a little bit sweet. It's big, orange and round, like you say.
是的。它有点甜。就像你说的，它又大又橙又圆。
People often start to harvest them around October. I'd say.
人们通常在十月左右开始收获它们。
Some people like to eat the seeds. But you can also scoop out with your spoon.
有些人喜欢吃种子。但你也可以用勺子挖出来。
You can take out some of the meat, some of the filling.
你可以取出一些果肉，一些馅料。
And that's what we use to create this pumpkin pie.
这就是我们用来做南瓜派的东西。
Very good. So pumpkin pie. Delicious food.
很好。所以南瓜派，美味的食物。
Now we also have a typical mashed potatoes with gravy.
现在我们还有典型的土豆泥配肉汁。
All right. I love mashed potatoes. Mashed means to squish or to break down or to push down.
好的。我喜欢土豆泥。Mashed 意思是压碎、捣碎或压扁。
And so mashed potatoes, you have a normal potato and you mix up all the potatoes together.
所以土豆泥，你有一个普通的土豆，然后把所有土豆混合在一起。
So it's kind of like soft and creamy.
所以它有点像柔软细腻的。
Yeah. It almost becomes like a paste or almost like, let's say, like ice cream, but not cold.
是的。它几乎变成糊状，或者像，比如说，冰淇淋，但不冷。
Not cold and not sweet. But yeah, that's the consistency. That's what it feels like.
不冷也不甜。但没错，就是那种质地。就是那种感觉。
And so when we eat potatoes like this, in America, we often like to eat it with a sauce.
所以当我们这样吃土豆时，在美国，我们通常喜欢配酱汁吃。
And the sauce that we eat with mashed potatoes is called gravy.
和土豆泥一起吃的酱汁叫做肉汁。
Gravy. And now gravy is usually made out of what?
肉汁。那么肉汁通常是用什么做的？
Gravy is made from... Well, you can make different kinds of gravy.
肉汁是用... 嗯，你可以做不同种类的肉汁。
But the way that we make it at my house is we take all of the juice from the turkey.
但在我家，我们做肉汁的方法是取所有火鸡的汁水。
Because when you bake a turkey in the oven, on the bottom of the pan you'll get some liquid, some water, some fat.
因为当你在烤箱里烤火鸡时，锅底会有一些液体、一些水、一些脂肪。
And you use that to make a gravy. So it's brown and it's very salty and delicious.
然后你用这些来做肉汁。所以它是棕色的，很咸，很美味。
Awesome. Sounds delicious. And to end things, we have stuffing.
太棒了。听起来很好吃。最后，我们还有填料。
Now this stuffing goes inside the turkey, right? But then you take it out.
这个填料是放在火鸡里面的，对吧？但然后你把它拿出来。
That's right. So stuffing, we talk about stuffing in general as being something that you put inside something else.
没错。所以填料，我们通常说填料是指放在其他东西里面的东西。
So if I have a stuffed animal, he has some cotton inside or whatever.
所以如果我有一个毛绒玩具，它里面有一些棉花之类的。
But if you have a turkey, you take out all of the organs, the heart, the liver.
但如果你有一只火鸡，你会取出所有内脏，心脏、肝脏。
You take those parts out because we don't eat those.
你取出那些部分，因为我们不吃那些。
And you put some bread, onions and vegetables inside the turkey to cook.
然后你把一些面包、洋葱和蔬菜放进火鸡里一起烤。
And then you take it out and you eat it. So it tastes a bit like turkey and meat, but it's very delicious.
然后你拿出来吃。所以它尝起来有点火鸡和肉的味道，但非常美味。
But you eat it apart, kind of like let's say rice.
但你分开吃，有点像，比如说，米饭。
Like a side dish.
像一道配菜。
All right. It sounds delicious. And obviously it's a very big meal, but very, very common, a traditional holiday in the United States.
好的。听起来很好吃。显然这是一顿大餐，但在美国非常非常常见，是传统的节日。
It's very fun to celebrate as well. You get together with family and you have this nice meal together.
庆祝起来也很有趣。你和家人聚在一起，一起享用这顿美餐。
That's right. It's a wonderful holiday. And we'll be talking a bit about it in a second.
没错。这是一个很棒的节日。我们一会儿会再聊一聊。
But let's just take one more listen to today's dialogue.
但让我们再听一遍今天的对话。
So what are you doing for Thanksgiving?
那你感恩节打算做什么？
Not much, really. It's more of an American tradition. So back home, we don't really celebrate it.
没什么特别的。这更像是美国的传统。所以在我家乡，我们不怎么庆祝。
In fact, I'm not even sure of what exactly is being celebrated.
事实上，我甚至不确定到底在庆祝什么。
Well, you know, it's a time to get together with all your family and be thankful for everything.
嗯，你知道，这是一个和家人聚在一起，感恩一切的时刻。
Yeah, but how did this holiday come to be?
是的，但这个节日是怎么来的？
Well, the first settlers of Massachusetts arrived there because of religious persecution from England and King James.
嗯，马萨诸塞州的第一批定居者是因为英格兰和詹姆斯国王的宗教迫害而到达那里的。
Once in the New World, they befriended a native named Squanto who taught them how to harvest food from the area, such as corn.
到了新世界后，他们结识了一位名叫斯匡托的当地人，他教他们如何收获当地的食物，比如玉米。
And then what happened?
然后发生了什么？
Well, they had enough harvest for the next winter, and in celebration, they decided to have a big feast with the natives,
嗯，他们有足够的收成过下一个冬天，为了庆祝，他们决定和当地人一起举办一场盛宴，
giving thanks to the land and everyone for their food, health and new lives.
感谢土地和每个人赐予他们食物、健康和新的生活。
Interesting. I am amazed how big and delicious Thanksgiving dinners are.
有趣。我很惊讶感恩节大餐如此丰盛美味。
Come to my house for Thanksgiving. We're having turkey, pumpkin pie, mashed potatoes with gravy and lots of stuffing.
来我家过感恩节吧。我们有火鸡、南瓜派、土豆泥配肉汁，还有很多填料。
Count me in.
算我一个。
All right, so Thanksgiving is a national holiday. Now, is it you said it's a Thursday.
好的，所以感恩节是一个全国性的节日。你说它是在星期四。
It's always on Thursday.
总是在星期四。
So you get that Thursday off from school, from work and everything.
所以星期四你从学校、工作和所有事情中放假。
You get Thursday and Friday.
你星期四和星期五都放假。
So you get two days.
所以你有两天假。
Yeah, it's a four day weekend.
是的，这是一个四天的长周末。
Oh, nice.
哦，不错。
And it's a wonderful holiday because it's something that everybody in America can celebrate.
这是一个很棒的节日，因为这是每个美国人都能庆祝的节日。
Because, you know, for Christmas, for example, some people don't celebrate Christmas.
因为，你知道，比如圣诞节，有些人不庆祝圣诞节。
Or you don't really get holiday time off during the summer for everyone, maybe just the schoolchildren.
或者夏天不是每个人都有假期，可能只有学生有。
And so this is actually a nice holiday because everybody is home.
所以这实际上是一个很好的节日，因为每个人都在家。
Right. So it doesn't have a religious connotation because you're talking about, you know, the settlers and how they arrived there
对。所以它没有宗教含义，因为你说的是，你知道，定居者以及他们如何到达那里
and they survived a harsh winter.
并熬过了一个严冬。
And so, as you say, it's kind of like a neutral holiday where you just it's a good excuse to get together, have a big meal
所以，如你所说，这有点像中性的节日，只是一个很好的借口聚在一起，吃一顿大餐
and just spend quality time with the family.
并和家人共度美好时光。
That's right. You cook all day. You eat. You watch some football on TV.
没错。你整天做饭。你吃。你看电视上的橄榄球赛。
You spend some time with your family and you fall asleep very, very full.
你和家人待在一起，然后吃得饱饱的睡着了。
So this is another very interesting thing is that usually on TV, because everyone is home,
所以另一件非常有趣的事情是，通常电视上，因为每个人都在家，
everyone is having dinner or spending time with each other, they will have a football game on TV for Thanksgiving.
每个人都在吃晚餐或互相陪伴，感恩节电视上会有一场橄榄球赛。
That's right. So everyone's sitting around eating dinner and then there's a football game on the TV.
没错。所以每个人都围坐着吃晚餐，然后电视上在放橄榄球赛。
Wow. So that kind of that's kind of bad for the football players that have to be playing on Thanksgiving Day.
哇。所以这对那些必须在感恩节打球的橄榄球运动员来说有点糟糕。
Yeah, but they get all hungry, you know, out there on the field and they get to go home and eat a big turkey.
是的，但他们会在球场上饿，然后回家吃大火鸡。
And have a big meal. It's very, very interesting.
吃一顿大餐。非常非常有趣。
We'll put some pictures of the food that is commonly served on this holiday.
我们会放一些这个节日常见食物的图片。
And it would be interesting to know if I know a lot of our listeners are not originally from the United States.
而且知道我们很多听众并非来自美国，这会很有趣。
So if you are there, tell us if you've celebrated it or how have you seen it or will you celebrate it or any story that you can share with us.
所以如果你在那里，告诉我们你是否庆祝过，或者你如何看待它，或者你会庆祝吗，或者任何你可以分享的故事。
That's right. We are very excited to hear this from you and we wish you all a very happy Thanksgiving.
没错。我们很期待听到你的分享，并祝大家感恩节快乐。
Visit our site EnglishPod.com to tell us more.
访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，告诉我们更多信息。
All right. We'll see you guys there. Bye.
好的。我们到时候见。拜拜。